Inventory of the John Damian Murphy Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John Damian Murphy Papers
1943-1949
79095
Murphy, John Damian, 1896-
14 manuscript boxes (5.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Consists of court proceedings, investigative reports, regulations, orders, memoranda, printed matter, and photographs relating to trials held on Guam, 1946-1949, of Japanese military personnel for war crimes.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1979
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1896 August 19 Born, Newton, Kansas
1915-1918 Student, University of Kansas
1918 Enlisted as apprentice seaman, United States Naval Reserve
1922-1923 Student, Torpedo School, United States Navy, Newport, Rhode Island
1927-1930 Associated with George Washington University Law School, Washington, D.C.
1929 JD, George Washington University, Washington, D.C.
1932-1933 Executive officer, USS Mindanao, Asiatic station
1933-1936 U.S. Army Chemical Warfare School
1938-1939 Commander, USS Sicard
1939-1942 Chief of division, Office of Judge Advocate General (Navy)
1942-1944 Commander, USS Alcor, fleet repair and flagship
1945 Graduated from Joint Army-Navy Staff College, Washington, D.C. Legal officer, U.S. Pacific Fleet staff Planning officer, 7th Amphibious Force, U.S. Pacific Fleet
1946 Naval aide, Justice Frank Murphy, special U.S. representative to the Philippine Republic
1946-1949 Director, War Crimes, U.S. Pacific Fleet
1955 Bachelor of science, American University, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of John Damian Murphy consist of court proceedings, investigative reports, regulations, orders, memoranda, printed matter, and photographs, relating to trials held on Guam, 1946-1949, of Japanese military personnel for war crimes.
Trials of accused Japanese war criminals were held on Guam and Kwajalein by the War Crimes Branch of the Pacific Fleet, U.S. Navy, from 1945 through 1949. They were held under the auspices of the Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers (SCAP), which oversaw war crimes trials in Japan and the Asia-Pacific region until 1951.
Major accused war criminals were tried by the International Military Tribunal for the Far East, also known as the Tokyo Trial. Other war crimes trials for alleged minor war criminals were held in the countries and territories invaded and occupied by the Japanese. The U.S. Navy had jurisdiction over some of these trials.
Admiral John D. Murphy, a lawyer who had risen through the ranks from enlisted man, served as War Crimes Director. Naval trials were conducted by the Office of the Judge Advocate General (Navy) under the Navy Division of the War Crimes Office. The War Crimes Office was a central agency in the War Department to coordinate with the Departments of State, War, and the Navy.
Investigations into alleged war crimes were conducted by U.S. Navy personnel. The courts were known as military commissions, and consisted of five to seven U.S. military officers. The accused were tried for minor war crimes, such as murder and ill-treatment of prisoners, and included personnel of the Imperial Japanese Navy and the Imperial Japanese Army. The accused were afforded defense counsel, both Allied and Japanese. Rules of evidence were relaxed. Summaries of trials were regularly submitted to the Japanese government via SCAP memoranda.
Related material at the Hoover Institution includes records of the International Military Tribunal for the Far East. The National Archives in College Park, Maryland, holds official records of the U.S. agencies involved in these war crimes trials
The John D. Murphy papers were acquired in 1979.
Source: Welch, Jeanie M., "Without a Hangman, Without a Rope: Navy War Crimes Trials after World War II," International Journal of Naval History 1 (April 2002). Available from the International Journal of Naval History.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
United States. Navy--Officers.; War crime trials--Guam.; World War, 1939-1945--Atrocities.; World War, 1939-1945--Japan.
Container List
- Records of court proceedings and related materials (Box 1)
  - Hiroo Koichi and others, 1947, undated (Folder 1: 1-2)
  - Ajioka Yamada, 1947, undated (Folder 1: 3-4)
  - Kazuo Nakamura, 1947-1948 (Folder 1: 5-6)
  - Kazuharu Yamamoto and others, 1948 (Folder 1: 7-10)
  - Masashi Kobayashi, 1948 (Folder 1: 11)
  - Sadae Inoue and Tokuchi Tada, 1949 (Box-folder 2: 1-3)
  - Susumo Kawasaki and others, 1946-1947 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Chisato Oishi, 1946-1947 (Folder 2: 5-6)
  - Takamune Kato, 1946 (Folder 2: 7-8)
  - Yoshie Tachibana and others, Volume I, 1946-1948 (Folder 2: 9-10)
  - Hiroshi Iwanami and others (Box 3)
    - Volume II, 1947 (Folder 3: 1-3)
    - Volume III, 1946-1947 (Folder 3: 4-5)
  - Shimpei Asano and others
    - Volume I, 1947 (Folder 3: 6-7)
    - Volume II, 1947 (Folder 3: 8-10)
  - Hiroshi Iwanami and others, Volume I, 1947 (Box-folder 4: 1-3)
  - Fumio Inoue
    - Volume I, 1947 (Folder 4: 4-6)
    - Volume II, 1947 (Folder 4: 7-10)
  - Seisaku Wakabayashi (Box 5)
    - Volume I, 1948 (Folder 5: 1-3)
    - Volume II, 1948 (Folder 5: 4-5)
    - Volume III, 1948 (Folder 5: 6-7)
    - Volume IV, 1948 (Folder 5: 8-10)
  - Masashi Kobayashi (Box 6)
    - Volume II, 1948 (Folder 6: 1-4)
    - Volume III, 1948 (Folder 6: 5-8)
    - Volume IV, 1948 (Folder 6: 9-11)
- John D. Murphy (Box 7)
  - Public relations file, 1947-1948 (Folder 7: 1-5)
  - General office file, 1942-1946. (Folder 7: 6)
    Memoranda and order
- Far East Command, 1948. (Folder 7: 7)
  Press releases
- Office of Strategic Services (OSS), 1944 May – August. (Folder 7: 8-10)
  Reports
- Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers (SCAP), 1946-1948 (Folder 7: 11-14)
- United States Pacific Fleet, 1945-1948. (Folder 7: 15)
  Memoranda
- Records of court proceedings and related materials--United States of America vs. Tomoyuki Yamashita and others, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Reply of Judge Advocate, delivered by David Bolton, in support of jurisdiction of military commission with regard to administration of justice in the Marshall Islands, 1944 (Folder 8: 2)
- Records of court proceedings
  - Opening argument for prosecution, delivered by Edward L. Field, undated (Folder 8: 3)
  - Outline of opening argument for prosecution, delivered by David Bolton, undated (Folder 8: 4)
  - Closing argument for prosecution, including the case of Masashi Kobayashi, delivered by David Bolton, undated (Folder 8: 5-6)
  - Closing and final argument in the case of Masashi Kobayashi, delivered by defense counsel, Junjiri Takano, and Martin E. Carlson, 1948 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Index to Judge Advocate General's closing argument, undated (Folder 8: 8)
  - Defense opening statement, part I, by Ichiro Kiyose, and part II, by Kenzo Takayanagi, undated (Folder 8: 9)
- Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers (SCAP)
  - Reviews of war crimes cases, 1945-1947 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Records of specifications, 1946-1946, undated. (Folder 8: 11-12)
    Memoranda, notes, and related materials
  - Report of John A. Duffy on Noboru Ariyama and Atsushi Sato, 1946 (Folder 8: 13)
- United States Pacific Fleet, 1946-1948. (Folder 8: 14-15)
  Brochure, memoranda, note, telegram, and related materials
- Records of court proceedings and related materials (Box 9)
  - Tadashi Teraki
    - Volume I, 1949 (Folder 9: 1-2)
    - Volume II, 1946-1948 (Folder 9: 3-4)
  - Chuichi Hara, Volume V, 1944-1948 (Folder 9: 5-7)
  - Akira Tokunaga, Yoshio Takahashi, and Shigeo Koyama, 1948-1949 (Folder 9: 8-10)
  - Chuichi Hara (Box 10)
    - Volume I, 1948 (Folder 10: 1-2)
    - Volume II, 1948 (Folder 10: 3-4)
    - Volume III, 1948-1949 (Folder 10: 5-6)
    - Volume IV, 1946-1948, undated (Folder 10: 7-9)
  - Seishi Katsumi
    - Volume I, 1948 (Folder 10: 10-12)
    - Volume II, 1948 (Folder 10: 13-14)
  - Tomeroku Danzaki and Yoshiharu Yoshinuma, 1946 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
  - Furuki Hidesaku
    - Volume I, 1947. (Folder 11: 3-5)
      Prefixed documents
    - Volume II, 1947. (Folder 11: 6-8)
      Appended documents--Exhibits
  - Commander, Marianas Area, United States Pacific Fleet, 1946-1947 (Folder 11: 9-10)
  - Nasayoshi Takano, 1946 (Folder 11: 11)
- Navy News, 1947 (Box-folder 12: 1)
- Final ramp report of Commander, Marianas Area, Guam, undated (Folder 12: 2)
- Civil Affairs Handbook, Japan, sections I, XIII, XIV, and XVI, 1943-1944 (Folder 12: 3-4)
- Japan and the Japanese: A Military Power We Must Defeat: A Pacific Problem We Must Solve, 1944; What Shall Be Done with the War Criminals? 1944; and Misconduct and Line of Duty, 1945 (Folder 12: 5)
- International Law Documents, 1943, Naval War College, 1945 (Folder 12: 6)
- Radio report of the Far East, Number 73, Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service, Federal Communications Commission, 1945, undated. (Folder 12: 7)
  Includes list, "Japanese Ministries: Table of Administrative Structure"
- Department of Navy, 1947. (Folder 12: 8)
  List of officers, Bureau of Naval Personnel, and memorandum
- Printed matter, 1945-1947 (Folder 12: 9)
- Miscellaneous official documents, 1946, undated. (Folder 12: 10)
  Includes analysis of documentary evidence, memoranda, personal letters, and related materials
- Miscellany, 1947, undated. (Folder 12: 11)
  Includes 7 photographic prints depicting Kisaku Daigen
- Clippings and printed matter, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 13: 1)
- Department of the Navy
  - Address by James J. Robinson, 1945 (Folder 13: 2)
  - Lectures, 1947. "The Determination of Over-all Logistic Requirements," by E. E. Geiselman, and "National Policy and Naval Strategy," by J. E. Wallace (Folder 13: 3)
  - Letter to John Murphy from Lewis S. Parks, 1948 (Folder 13: 4)
  - Lists of flag officers on active duty, naval personnel, and flag and general officers in Guam, 1947-1949 (Folder 13: 5)
  - Memoranda, 1947-1949 (Folder 13: 6)
  - Speeches
    - Unidentified, undated (Folder 13: 7)
    - Outline of speech on war crimes prepared for Arthur G. Robinson, undated (Folder 13: 8)
    - "The First Year of Unification," W. John Kenney, Navy Industrial Association, San Francisco, 1948 (Folder 13: 9)
  - Statement by John L. Sullivan before the President's Air Policy Commission, Department of Commerce, Washington, D.C., 1947 (Folder 13: 10)
  - Speakers' kit, parts II and III, 1947. (Folder 13: 11)
    Includes list of suggested speech topics
- Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers (SCAP), 1947-1948. (Folder 13: 12)
- Telephone directories
  - General, 1946-1949 (Folder 13: 13)
  - Guam area, 1948 (Folder 13: 14)
- Miscellany, 1945-1948 (Folder 13: 15)
- Chronology of liquor laws and regulations, undated (Box-folder 14: 1)
- Clippings, 1946 (Folder 14: 2)
- Commonwealth of Australia, 1945. (Folder 14: 3)
  Legal document relating to trial and punishment of war criminals
- United States Navy--Military Government of Guam
  - Legal records and memoranda, 1945-1946 (Folder 14: 4)
  - Records of proclamations, 1946, undated (Folder 14: 5)
- 11 photographic prints depicting wrecked plane, undated (Folder 14: 6)
- List of Japanese rules, laws, and regulations pertaining to prisoners of war, 1947. (Folder 14: 7)
  Certified translated copy from Japanese
- Reports
  - Undated. (Folder 14: 8)
    Includes one on command responsibility in war crime situation
  - Japanese violations of the laws of war, 1944 (Folder 14: 9)
  - Conferences and Pearl Harbor operation, 1945 (Folder 14: 10)
- Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers (SCAP)
  - General, 1945-1946. (Folder 14: 11)
    List of specifications and memoranda
  - "Japan's Decision to Fight,", 1945. (Folder 14: 12)
    Research report
- United States Army, 1945-1947, undated. (Folder 14: 13)
  Legal record, memoranda, and special orders. Includes court proceedings relating to the determination of outline of procedure for trial of accused war criminals
- Miscellany, undated (Folder 14: 15)